Next, we are going to talk about infant CPR,
which applies to any baby up to one year old.
Much like with older children, cardiac arrest in infants
usually starts as a respiratory issue
rather than a heart problem.
While the situation is different,
you will find that the core steps of the rescue
remain the same ones you have already learned.
One, ensure the scene is safe before you approach.
Two, assess the infant for responsiveness.
Because a baby can't tell you if they are okay,
you will check for a reaction
by tickling the infant's foot or pinching their toe.
While you do this, check for breathing.
Is their chest rising and falling?
Look for those severe signs we discussed earlier,
a lack of consciousness or blue lips and extremities.
If the baby moves when you tickle their foot,
that is a great sign,
but you should still call 911
if you feel something is wrong.
Three, call for help and activate 911.
If the infant is unresponsive and not breathing,
call 911 immediately and place them on speakerphone
so you can begin CPR while talking to the dispatcher.
There is one major difference for infants
if you are alone and do not have a phone.
You should perform five rounds of CPR first.
If the baby is still unresponsive after those rounds,
pick the baby up and take them with you
to find a phone or help.
You never want to leave an infant alone
while you go to get assistance.